Atul Meshram

Senior Product Designer

- **)** +91-8050606549
- **⋄** atulmeshram.github.io

Summary

I am a Product Designer & Engineer. I love to interact with people to understand their expectations and unpleasant experiences from the products and use their insights to create simple and beautiful interfaces that have a high degree of usability. I design product concepts from prototyping to production.

Experience

Bengaluru, INDIA

o9 Solutions — Senior Product Designer

May 2018 - Present Designed and prototyped dozens of widgets and features for web, mobile, and desktop applications by establishing a comprehensive design system that varied from small, one-week prototypes that explored specific interactions to large-scale, multi-month projects targeted for the launch.

Case Study

Bengaluru, INDIA

Accolite — UX Designer

Jan 2016 - Mar 2018 Worked on various products and designed experiences for

multiple clients: BT, Standard Chartered, and FedEX.

Education

October 2017 - Feb

University of California, San Diego — Interaction

2018

Design Specialisation

Score 9.9

Online through Coursera.

Relevant Coursework:

User Experience - Research & Prototyping,

Human-Centered Design, Design Principles,

Social Computing, Input and Interaction, Information Design,

Designing, Running, and Analyzing Experiments.

July 2013 - May 2016

NIT Karnataka — Masters of Computer Applications

8.5 CGPA Specialisation in Computer Graphics

Relevant Coursework: Cryptography, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Networks, Web Applications, Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Management Systems, Operating

Systems, Computer Graphics.

Major Project: Switch.

Skills

Sketch

Figma

Framer

ProtoPie Flinto

Adobe After Effects

Blender

JavaScript (ES6)

HTML5 & CSS3

ReactJS

ThreeJS

UX: Interaction Design, Motion Design,

Visual Design, User Research,

Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Heuristic Evaluation, Usability Testing, Comparative Analysis, Mobile App Design, and Web App Design.

Leadership: UX Strategy & Planning, Team Coordination, Project Planning, Work Review, and Training & Mentorship.

Highlights

'The Inspirer'

Award for 'Igniting Innovation and Creativity' at o9 Solutions.

'Smart Bot'

Winner of o9 Hackathon 2019.

'All-Rounder'

Award for multiple design and development client projects at Accolite.

'Rockstar'

Award by BT for solving design problems.

Placement Cell Portal

Developer and Student Data Administrator.